Inventory of the John Ehrlichman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John Ehrlichman papers
1963-1982
88007
Hoover Institution Archives
114 manuscript boxes, 11 oversize boxes (60.4 linear feet)
Photocopies of notes of White House meetings, memoranda, letters, and reports, relating primarily to Nixon administration domestic policy, policy relating to the Vietnam War, the 1972 presidential elections, and the Watergate controversy; and sound recordings of television news programs and interviews, Congressional hearings, and trial proceedings relating to the Watergate affair. In part, photocopy.
Ehrlichman, John.
Access
Boxes 18-137 closed.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988, with increments received in later years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
In part, originals located in: National Archives, Washington, D.C.
Related Collection(s)
John D. Ehrlichman Papers, White House Special Files, 01/20/1969 - 04/30/1973. Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum.
Biographical Note
1925 March 20 Born, Tacoma, Washington
1952-1968 Partner, Hullin, Ehrlichman, Roberts & Hodge, Seattle, Washington
1968 Director, Convention Activities; Tour Director, Nixon for President campaign
1969 Counsel to President Richard Nixon
1969-1973 Assistant to the President for Domestic Affairs; Executive Director, Domestic Council
1970-1973 Member, Federal Property Review Board
1971-1973 Member, President's Council on International Economic Policy
1976 Author, The Company
1976-1978 Inmate, Swift Trail Federal Prison Camp, Safford, Arizona
1978-1980 Radio and television commentator
1979 Author, The Whole Truth
1982 Author, Witness to Power
1986 Author, The China Card
1999 Died, Atlanta, Georgia
Scope and Content of Collection
Photocopies of notes of White House meetings, memoranda, letters, and reports, relating primarily to Nixon administration domestic policy, policy relating to the Vietnam War, the 1972 presidential elections, and the Watergate controversy; and sound recordings of television news programs and interviews, Congressional hearings, and trial proceedings relating to the Watergate affair. In part, photocopy.
Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Watergate Affair, 1972-1974.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; Audiotapes.
- NIXON ADMINISTRATION FILE, Appendix A - Documents: Files, 1963-1982 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Primarily meeting notes; also includes schedules, memoranda, letters, telephone notes, charts, reports and statements relating to domestic policy, Cabinet and Executive Department personnel, the Vietnam War (including the CBS-Westmoreland controversy over enemy force estimates), Watergate, and the 1972 presidential election. Arranged chronologically; see Appendix A for detailed box list (prepared by the Archives of Artists of New Mexico and the Southwest).
  - Press: 1969 Evaluation of Writers & T.V. - R. Z. Klein Cross-ref. to 6 mo. game plan (28 pages) (Box 1)
  - Connally-the econ. boss G. Sh. defer J.C.-anti semetic (2 pages), Undated
  - H. notes re: Trento Changes- Where H, C, E were in May, June (1 page), 1969
  - Rogers (& HAK), Change E.L.R. (1 page), undated
  - E's To-Do List (4 pages), 1969 February 5
  - Burger Letters to Mitchell (6 pages), 1969 April 4 - 1971 October 13
  - Six Month Game Plan/Notes (10 pages), 1969 July
  - Image Analysis & Game Plans (contents missing pages), 1969 September
  - Haynesworth/V. Nam
  - Family, Reaction to Don's complaints, Move funds to Bebe (6 pages), 1969 September 4
  - Rocky, Agnew, Senators by name, WWH-golf-other expenses (5 pages), 1969 September 5
  - Demonstrations-R.N. Reaction, Personnel Shifts, Haynesworth (10 pages), 1969 October 1
  - TT-Scott-Hruska-Allott Cook-Griffen, Harlow-A.G.-Young-Cook-Beaulieu-, E.-Symington (Haynesworth: The War) (10 pages), 1969 October 2
  - Anti-Symington Pincus/Paul (Notes), Strategy Committee (2 pages), 1969 October 7
  - Haynesworth, DPM- (FAP), paucity w/ Rumsfeld (3 pages), 1969 October 8
  - Press-Planted Q's, Order Ford to Impeach Douglas (2 pages), 1969 October 9
  - Haynesworth, qt. pressure/appt a jew (2 pages), 1969 October
  - TT and Ash Council/Reorg. (4 pages), 1969 October 22
  - J.B.C. Volunteers, R.N. & Rock Music, Fec.-A.B.-private writings, Myth of Independence (12 pages), 1969 October 23
  - Agnew-schism (Notes), Kraft Hugh Scott, Press Handle w/ cool contempt (5 pages), 1969 October 27
  - Austin Geriatric Center/LBJ (9 pages), 1969 November-December 2
  - Agnew trip (Notes), an anwar dilemme (answered) (6 pages), 1969 November 14
  - JNM, RN mistakes-Abernathy-etc- (Notes), Speech writers-"moving power" (6 pages), 1969 December 2
  - TT-Haynesworth Conf. (6 pages), 1969 December 4
  - Fitzgerald to Bob (Notes), No budget appeals to TT, Tipping WH help (6 pages), 1969 December 19
  - 3 bil. stockpile, AB-Alexander Tax reform, Veto Hew/WH Conferences (3 pages), 1969 December 20
  - RN on The Press (5 pages), 1969 December 29
  - Dept. Budget Reviews (Notes), Stockpiler (12 pages), 1969
  - Budget Outlook '70-71 w/ changes, Asset Sales/Murphy Finch (3 pages), 1970 January 3
  - Don to H. Kalmbach, WWH - Use of golf course, Hoffe (2 pages), 1970 January 8?
  - Private Schools in South (Notes), SOTU, Cut overseas personnel (3 pages), 1970 January 9
  - HAK opinion of Mayo (Personnel), LBJ, Helms must go, HAK's area-Reorg., DuBridge (6 pages), 1970 January 10
  - SOTU (Notes), Leak parts (4 pages), 1970 January 16
  - Memo to TT, Burns-say at McC dinner AB was 1st choice (Missing pages), 1970 January 17
  - Carswell (Notes), Line for Cronkhite re TT (2 pages), 1970 January 19
  - Black Panthers (Notes) (2 pages), 1970 January 29
  - Southern Schools (Notes), VP Agnew (4 pages), 1970 January 30
  - The Presidency (Notes), personality of Admin., Taft and T.R., Press and TV (5 pages), 1970 February 2
  - TT Mitchell G.S.C.-Finch-E. (Notes), (Southern Schools) (5 pages), 1970 February 7
  - Agnew health role, Agnew speech writer (1 page), 1970 February 11
  - School-deseg. Panetta (Notes), Econ. (TT ple.), Agnew (3 pages), 1970 February 12
  - TT + JE Hoover (Notes), *Hooverisms (41 pages), 1970 February 26
  - Agnew (Notes) (4 pages), 1970 March 8
  - FED, LAOS (Notes), Ripon, Ivy League, Finch (4 pages), 1970 March 16
  - "How the TT Works" (Notes), DeSeg Stunt-game plan (Start?) (TT BH E), Carswell (4 pages), 1970 March 25
  - Carswell, TT RK E (3 pages), 1970 March 26
  - Agnew-GSA-Eastern States (Notes), Carswell (TT, H, E, Woods, Warren), Peace Corps (2 pages), 1970 March 31
  - EMK (Notes), Douglas Impeachment (8 pages), 1970 April 16
  - HAK (Diary), Shows me Cambodia, Attack plans- (1 page), 1970 April 25
  - Economy-Rinfret (TT Ph.) Need spokesman, E get in, Bail out brokers (8 pages), 1970 April 27-28
  - TT Walk pre Cambodia, JNM to treasury (1 page), 1970 April 28
  - Rogers opposed to Cambodia Maneuver, Pete Upset, PN looped/Burger brings note (1 page), 1970 April 30
  - re: TT Mtg w/ Kent State kids (Notes) (4 pages), 1970 May 9
  - Agnew re. press (Notes), TT pb. (3 pages), 1970 May 20
  - Burns-penance (Notes), Weinberger ONB (TT E), Hak - NYC Speech orders, Cabinet / Hickel (3 pages), 1970 May 21
  - Cabinet for Nov. (TT.H.E.), Finch, Hickel Letter (3 pages), 1970 May 25
  - Agnew-DPM re, Black Violence (Missing pages), 1970 May 26
  - Hickel/TT: run for Gov. (Diary) (1 page), 1970 May 27
  - Hickel-run for Gov., TT-Hickel-E (2 pages), 1970 May 28
  - Finch HEW, New Nat'l Party, Cabinet, Population (4 pages), 1970 June 3
  - Penn Central-Guthrie (TT-Flan-H-E), Weinberger-om B (2 pages), 1970 June 4
  - Finch gives up HEW, Successor Q (1 page), 1970 June 5
  - Agnew & Joe (Diary), Rhodes, Fresh, 1970 June 16
  - Scranton Comm'n (TT-Seranton AG-Finch), (Kent State etc), marching orders, Joe Rhodes (8 pages), 1970 June 18
  - Agnew/Taft won't appear, 18 year vote Penn Central (TT-BNH-BT), Prime M. Wilson call (HE) (6 pages), 1970 June 19
  - Agnew & WH Staff (TT E), Hickel (6 pages), 1970 July 7
  - DESEGREGATION N B (TT/VP/AG), Schools (K/RF/BNH), South (23 pages), 1970 August 4
  - Timmons Report on Senate (Memo to TT), end-the-war-amendments, to for-aid bill, Saxbe story, Scott, Sneaky stories (Missing pages), 1970 August 8?
  - Budget (C.D.), Cabinet-Schultz-Morton, HAK, FAP, DESEG Housing (6 pages), 1970 August 9
  - DESEG-New Orleans Quota (TT Sh E) (5 pages), 1970 August 13
  - Sol. Gen. Griswold, E mtg. notes (6 pages), 1970 August 18
  - Solic. Gen'l-Parochial, TT H Scott, H. E. (3 pages), 1970 August 18
  - Parochial, DeRussey, OMB, Liberals, Congress & W. H. Staff, Mamie's dentist (6 pages), 1970 August 19
  - R. N. (Diary), Manson's, guilty (1 page), 1970 August 30
  - HAK not on TV (TT H E), Sex-Pot-Porno-Rock, Press, Agnew (2 pages), 1970 September 1
  - Freeze-out (Diary), Kevin Phillips controversy, Hickel, Romney, Morton (3 pages), 1970 September 10
  - The "Social Issue" (very N.B.), and our domestic policy-R.N. orders (11 pages), 1970 October
  - Origin of Controls (TT Sh. E), decides to can Hickel, Fear of Kidnap (14 pages), 1970 October 23
  - Hickel (Diary), Firing & after (4 pages), 1970 November
  - Agnew-TT supports line (TT VP), Campaign (P Buch), Economy issue (7 pages), 1970 November 1
  - Budget (TT Sh-CW-E), Cabinet-openings list (A/F one) (9 pages), 1970 November 4 (Box 2)
  - HAK (Diary), cienfuegos briefing (1 page), 1970 November 5
  - Distressed w/ AB re incomes policy (TT ph), Polit. strateg. blacks labor, Youth, Catholic, Jews, Italians (9 pages), 1970 November 16
  - Prep. For AB mtg. & Nam speech (TT-economists), Controls, oil, money supply (13 pages), 1970 November 19
  - Burns Meeting (4 pages), 1970 November 20
  - Ost-out (TT Sh. E), Budget, Oil prices (8 pages), 1970 November 23
  - Economy (TT Economist), Davis Bacon, Nam Speech, Fed (21 pages), 1970 November 30
  - Budget-space (TT Sh E), Burns - a problem (6 pages), 1970 December 1
  - TT Rates the Cabinet, esp. JNM (2 pages), 1970 December 3
  - Reorg-Cab of 8 (TT-Sh-Harper-CW-E), Budget PR-, CIA SST rejected (6 pages), 1970 December 5
  - More Cabinet, tentative Shuffle/Mitchell (3 pages), 1970 December 7
  - Cabinet, JBC, Bush, Rumsfeld (Diary), V TT, Romney (1 page), 1970 December 7
  - TT feeling overworked, use VP more, Kennedy + CIEP, Blue LK (3 pages), 1970 December 11
  - TT-Burns-E, Burns, TT Fed be liberal, B-CEA Errs, Incomes Policy, PR & E (7 pages), 1970 December 15
  - School Vouchers, Poff, Burns (TT Sh E), Connally/Base closings (3 pages), 1970 December 15
  - Economy (TT Sh HE), Economists to recruit (2 pages), 1970 December 16
  - Burger, Back trouble-Ryland (Diary), Crt gossip, Sch case lobbying (1 page), 1970 December 18
  - HAK & Schlesinger (TT-Sh-H.E.), Budget, VAT, Burns, Trends in '72 (6 pages), 1970 December 23
  - Connally (TT ple), Jewish hijackers (C.D.), Church & PR, 2nd yr.-CAB-Accomplishments (6 pages), 1970 December 26
  - P. Peterson Solomon (TT-Sh-E), 3d yr. be tough on Staff, Rumsfld. paternalism, Rev Sh/Peace Corps space, Nat'l, Nixon (11 pages), 1970 December 28
  - Budget (TT-JBC-Sh), VAT (CW-E), What mark will we leave??, Cambodia-bold-, Tax Ref - Reorg. (16 pages), 1970 December 29
  - Welfare (TT-Sh-DPM), Disraeli (E), 3 Rabbis (7 pages), 1970 December 30
  - Hugh Scott, E mtg. w/ notes (3 pages), 1971 January 5
  - Governors & Staff, NR-Nunn, Vat/Rev Sh, Connally, John Lindsay, Rocky (7 pages), 1971 January 5
  - Tax reform (TT-E-Sc), Cabinet reorg., Peace Corps, J.E. Hoover (5 pages), 1971 January 6
  - Medicine (TT E), T.V. Intellectuals, Hutchnecker, Life, Glasses, Unemp. & Glasses, Expansionist econ. (8 pages), 1971 January 9
  - P. Peterson-orders for Budget, VAT, Alsop-feed, Game Plan-Drowns (5 pages), undated
  - No Contact for 2 days (TT ph), SOTU dictates (Protest Amnesty), - of - when, press confs, Geo. Allen (8 pages), 1971 January 12
  - E.'s to do List (1 page), 1971 January 15
  - Econ- (TT-Sh-McC), Controls - poll pro (E), Davis - Bacon - suspend (6 pages), 1971 January 18
  - Open Collar (TT TT-Sh-RF-DR), Staff & Cab - Spokesmen rules (CW-H-E), WH rooms - who can use - PR (3 pages), 1971 January 19
  - Commerce-Stans (TT E), Lynn, Anti-trust - What is policy?, CPI - RR (5 pages), 1971 December 18
  - P. Peterson - in gp. (TT-HAK-E), Connally (Agnew), Build for future, Burns - TT - Furious, Morton - ass (?) an, P. McCloskey (4 pages), 1971 February 20
  - Sch Deseg. (TT Sh E), 18 year vote, Burns - adverse, PN to parks (6 pages), 1971 March 8
  - HAK - resignation threat, Blair Hse, Rogers - Mideast (1 page), 1971 March 8
  - Cabinet Rump Session (TT E), Counter - moves (2 pages), 1971 March 18
  - Allott & Schlesinger (TT/H/E), Cabinet Cabal - CD not by divine right, Wilbur Mill's family in, Counter-moves (5 pages), 1971 March 19
  - Corps of Eng. (TT-Sh-E), Abortion, Welfare, Reorg., Rump Cabinet (5 pages), 1971 March 23
  - May Day Demonstrations (Diary), concentration camp, be sure some police are hurt, McGovern (1 page), 1971 May
  - Pentagon Papers (Diary), J.C. To Be Econ Spokesman (4 pages), 1971 June
  - CHINA, Perrinos dinner, Young to conspiracy team (1 page), 1971 July 15
  - Agnew troubles/Dump (Diary), J.C. N's successor, E to advance China / Finch leave WH (1 page), 1971 July 20
  - Hoover (1 page), firing breakfast, aftermath letter (1 page), 1971 September 20
  - Krogh memo, How to screen s/ct, Nominees / Send Dean and Young (4 pages), 1971 September 24
  - Supreme Court (TT E), Poff, Powell, Friday, Byrd (2 pages), 1971 October 2
  - Supreme Ct., how Rehnquist, Powell chosen (1 page), 1971 October 25
  - Radford, Wellander (Diary), HAK, Moorer (5 pages), 1971 December, 1972 January
  - Dep Sec Def - not P Fian, Mitchell, Kissinger - protocol rank - (1 page), 1972 January 4
  - WASAG leak - Radford (TT H E), HAK & Press, Prosecute Jack Anderson (2 pages), 1972 January 5
  - Burns-the pay Board-Pessimism (TT/Sh/E), Geo. Boldt, State dept. & Rogers, HAK on J. C. succeed - J.C. a gentleman (8 pages), 1972 January 18
  - Rizzo's support (TT E), Wilbur Mills-family on ple. (4 pages), 1972 January 24
  - VAT-Back off (TT ple), CD (2 pages), 1972 February 2
  - Don N. - Marriotts (TT H E), Donny - Vesco SEC (2 pages), 1972 February 7
  - Don Nixon (Diary), Ed & Don Mtg., Fin details, Ed returns (2 pages), 1972 February 9
  - A. Burns - Showdown (VAT/TT/E), Rizzo (A/Fone), Jews - sly (4 pages), 1972 February 13
  - CABINET (TT Sh E), PENN CENTRAL, Connally - Lockheed (3 pages), 1972 February 15
  - K to be AG (TT/Kleindienst), Rel to Connally (E), Civ. Rts Issues (SH), Women judges - list, you fellows run the place - V TT (12 pages), 1972 February 16
  - Buchanen to resign (TT H E), Busing-Deseg, I.T.T. (3 pages), 1972 March 6
  - I.T.T. San Diego (TT H E), Damage Control, K asked hearing, New Hamp. primary prediction, Flanigan to P Peterson - biz (3 pages), 1972 March 6
  - RN to Hoover, ITT document, Verification (5 pages), 1972 March 21
  - Cabinet - no more mtings., Peterson disloyal (TT H/E), flush FAP, Rev Sh. (C.D.), Paroch. Sch aid, cut ARTS, Higher Ed, MIT, Don't move left - McGovern will be nominee, AE1, Press-force feed (Colson) (assume this is all a reaction to a talk w/ C. Colson), Enemy, Create new establishment, Major Daley, Need for a new party, ITT - a smear (9 pages), 1972 April 21
  - Volpe, typical appointment (2 pages), 1972 April 23
  - A: 2 great inspirations:, Rizzo A's protege (TT Annenberg), Keep Scott out (JNM - E), -Calif. - Norton Simon, Daughter an alternate - Reagan (5 pages), 1972 May 9
  - Abrams - read Churchill, Geo. Wallace (TT/H/Haig), Protecting TT - keep girls home (Colson E), Fire Rowley, Gun Control (5 pages), 1972 May 16
  - Wallace Shot (Diary), J.C. leaving (2 pages), 1972 May
  - W/G report, I urge JNM leave, CMG replacer (3 pages), 1972 June
  - Busing - Moratorium, Parochial Sch - aid, DDT, Erickson or Justice, Ambassadors (5 pages), 1972 June 15
  - Death Penalty (TT/E/HAK), Bumper stickers (S. C), Buttons-text (6 pages), 1972 July 5
  - Control Colson (TT E (re: Gray)), Agnew & his staff (Dean/K/Liddy/), Reagan (McGruder), Overview-TT-vote of no confid. (TT H/E/McGregor), in JNM & Magruder Malek Timmons (12 pages), 1972 July 6
  - Watergate: Walters & Gary (TT H E), Campaign issues (SC), Woodrow Wilson-chippy chaser, Drowns to Ceylon (3 pages), 1972 July 6
  - Clark McGregor - P Gray/CIA, nover talk to TT re W/G (TT E), CIA - no interest (SC) (2 pages), 1972 July 6
  - Agnew & press, Watergate: Holms & Walters (TT E ), Cover up (S. C.), Econ statistics BLS (11 pages), 1972 July 7
  - WGF-no coverup-full investign, no WH involvmt (TT E), Bitman (San C.), MacGruder resign sooner, Reps boycott all Cong. Comms. (2 pages), 1972 July 8
  - S C explan., 6/23 Helms etc. (TT/E) (4 pages), 1972 July 8
  - Jacobson of Texas, W/G Timing-post election (Kleindienst), Sloan. Stans/ Liddy/Jeb (Dean/E), TT pictures to RK Erickson, Vr Amendmt. / Jeb (3 pages), 1972 July 31
  - Kleindienst, JD, E (3 pages), 1972 July 31
  - Teeter-polls, Issues for '72 (6 pages), 1972 August 1
  - Colson Staff list (Kenrli) (3 pages), 1972 August 1
  - McGovern (TT), permissiveness-line (1 page), undated
  - Use IRS-O'Brien McGovern (TT/H/E), Football in desk drawer, Laird-rebelling, Romney, Erred in picking cabinet (3 pages), 1972 August 3
  - Romney/Wilkes Barre, Memo to GR; talking paper (1 page), 1972 August 10 (Box 3)
  - Discrim. Suits v LA. (Phone), Chicago, etc, Kleindienst (Missing pages), 1972 August 10
  - Romney letter resignat'n (TT H E), R's W.B. letter anquish, Let Rumsfeld go, Carlucci, Romney replaced with Van Dusen, Romney told not to go to platform Committee, A R Longworth -A/F one to convention, S. Alsop, RN's 4 Eulogies (3 pages), 1972 August 11
  - Romney report (TT Romney, Lincoln et al), on Wilkes-Barre (10 pages), 1972 August 11
  - Romney, TT Directive, Lenore's letter, Resignation (4 pages), 1972 August
  - TT Romney E / Romney W.B. report / RN-premonition, San Clemente / to leave 1/ will campaign (2 pages), 1972 October 31
  - Schultz-Walters (Phone), Re: O'Brien tax investig'n (7 pages), 1972 August 29
  - RN/premonition (Diary) (1 page) of assassination (1 page), 1972 October 31
  - Agnew-Indians (Sta), BIA Riot (Missing pages), 1972 November 10
  - Innaugural (TT/E), Restaffing, Ed, Julie, Colson, Innaug. Consultants A/Fone (3 pages), 1972 November 12
  - Hire Julie (TT/H/E), Agnew in '76 - won't help him, Budget-cuts (Camp David ), HAK is a rag mer. (* (scene)), Agnew-criteria-falls short-staff, Reorg-3 counsellors, Henry Jackson - Sec Def?, Restaffing, Rogers (8 pages), 1972 November 14
  - TT Ash/Malek Reorg-, H.E., Camp David (Ike) (3 pages), 1972 November 14
  - Flanigan (Restaff TT H E), Rogers (CD Aspen), Klein, Rumsfeld, Malek, Morton, ELR, C Colson (8 pages), 1972 November 16
  - J.B.C. reconfirm judges every 10 yrs/Restaff (TT Weinberger E) (TT-Sh P Peterson E), Weinberger, Offer to P.P., CIEP not worked-the Hak problem (DOD-Richardson) (9 pages), 1972 November 17
  - Restaff: (TT/Sh/E), Volcker (Dogwood/CD), P.. Peterson/shldn't stay - a Percy man, Flanigan, Casey, Dent, Rumsfeld, Walker, Bush, Weinberger, Report on Meany, Hodgeson, A secy Labor-ask Colson (7 pages), 1972 November 17
  - Bush / Restaff, Brennan (TT E then Rumsfeld), Rumsfeld session (Aspen Sh) (8 pages), 1972 November 20
  - Bush to RNC, RN to RNC in '60 (TT/Bush/E), Margin over McG. greatest (Aspen), "The in Clique," Klein, Finch leaving, Dole out (13 pages), 1972 November 20
  - Morton mtg. - Restaff, Allott-flanked Rogers-Dole to go (TT/Rog Morton/E), Rush/H - Rush mtg:, BIA Reorg Proposal (8 pages), 1972 November 21
  - P. Peterson (Restaff), Rumsfeld (TT H E), Helms 60, Schlesinger, HAK - don't smile in pics w/Tho, NSC Staff, Klein-retire or usia, Cabinet, Simon, Cole (9 pages), 1972 November 22
  - Timmons probs, Dole must go (TT/Timmons/H.E. Dogwood), BIA problems, Hauge letter re W.G. (8 pages), 1972 November 22
  - Eastland-keep Kleindienst, Klein-now / restaff (TT Hodgeson E), Hodgson, Rumsfeld, Don Rogers (4 pages), 1972 November 22
  - Romney out: terms, Volpe (TT E), Scali (TT Romney), Agnew (E Restaff), Indians, Kleindienst gone by summer, Rocky and JBC didn't want to be in cabinet, Don't sell yourself cheap, Laird, Sam Jackson (9 pages), 1972 November 24
  - Kleindienst 6 mo- (TT H E), Scali & HAK, Ambrose, Press Plan (2 pages), 1972 November 27
  - State restaff (Aspen), Blacks (TT/HAK/H/E), IRS, Sneed/Fay DAG, Nudge Douglas & Marshall off, Rizzo, Cutler. / Clifford on blacklist, Bush - TT will particip. in staffing RNC (4 pages), 1972 November 27
  - Gray/ill/ok, FBI leaks (TT/Kleindienst), FBI director (H.E), Justice Dept., Mrs. LBJ urges Harzog, Holdovers, Goldwater-Amb. to Mex 2 years, K want to be TT?, Ambition - fat rich, Clifford out, Cutler finished, Rogers-$10 mil, K leave-resign 7/, DAG - K: not Ambrose (13 pages), 1972 November 27
  - Bureaucracy (TT/Simon/E), IRS, Volelder, Cohen, Walker, Shultz, Don't be taken over by Wash. set, Foundations, Tax Reform, Tell Alexander, *Where to live-schools (7 pages), 1972 November 28
  - Impasse-DOJ cleanout (TT/Kleindienst/E), Dole-RNC-wants to stay (T/H/E), Kleindienst, Dent-Textiles, DOJ-Asst. A.G's, Dean asks help w/R.K.- (7 pages), 1972 November 28
  - Blacks, Ethnics (TT/Lynn/E), Cabinet-Dept to TT, Model Cities-flush, Ivy League, Jews, Biz council/break, Rocky & J.B.C. (4 pages), 1972 November 28
  - Southerners (TT/Dent/Sh/E), Bix Council, Stans/P.P. weak, Commerce no longer puppet of B.C., "Biz people who stood up," Brennan, GM Wilson was right, W+P Controls-when they work, How to run commerce, The Team, For. Trade, Labor, Energy, Live in Country, Bush a prep classmate-P Flan also, Dean for DAG, Nixon Library-Hebert to Cal soon/Cushman help (12 pages), 1972 November 29
  - Blacks (TT/E A/F one), Griswold/Bork, *Drop Ellsberg case, Gray-JNM can't send to senate, *E run energy from WH, Black southern Fed. judge (4 pages), 1972 November 30
  - Ivy League 1.7%, Clean up Gov't (TT/Colson/H/E/), Give state to J.B.C. (Key Biscayne), 5th Circuit, Defeated Senators: Allott, Miller, Chaffee, Jas Rhodes, Congress in new term - Blueprint, DOJ-Santarelli Wally Johnson-David's friend, P. Flan not HAK do ambassadors, Gray, Morton, Scali, Wash. Post. Scaife offer-suit 1,000 days, Colson's staff after Baroudy, Southerner on WH staff, AEI-change, Agnew-no fund raisers, JBC moven't/6 mo./so CC not RNC counsel, A new political party, New swimming pool (11 pages), 1972 December 1
  - Ambassadors - tell Rogers, HAK not ultra viries (?!) (TT/H/E), DOJ changes (KB?), Webster/IRS, Rumsfeld/NATO/rankles, PP - No, R.N. Estate Plan, Herb Klein-trying to find a job, P. Flan, Sh fire IRS' Walters, Schlesinger on Intellig., Cabinet, Agnew on V. Nam, Congress, New Party, 1972 December 2
  - Donny Nixon Jr. (G I Straub) (Cables-leaders) mtg (10 pages), 1972 December 4